Kerem Kocaer

SENIOR CYBERSECURITY CONSULTANT

kk@foxtheory.uk+44 7889 641 570Condon, Stockholm, Istanbul

Experienced security professional with a strong technical background, combined with a unique ability to understand the business and act as a bridge between senior management and technical teams. Able to lead and conduct security engagements of diverse complexities and deliver impactful reports.

EXPERIENCE

2019/10 - Present

London, UK

DARKLAB SECURITY | CTO

Providing technical cybersecurity consulting, including penetration testing, Red Team adversary emulation,

application security, security training.

2019/05 - Present

London, UK

WORKTOOLS | Co-founder, CTO

Building a Security, Compliance and Health monitoring platform, and enabling NCSC Cyber Essentials certification

for SMBs.

2018/09 - Present

London, UK

FOX THEORY | Freelance

Providing cybersecurity services, bug bounty assessments; developing IT solutions for the creative industries.

2015/06 - 2017/10 London, UK JPMORGAN CHASE & CO. | Vice President

Co-leading the Global Red Team; Managing and conducting cybersecurity assessments, including adversary emulation, penetration testing, product evaluations.

2014/09 – 2015/06

PWC UK | Manager

London, UK

Managing the Threat & Vulnerability team, leading and conducting Red Team engagements, malware development, phishing campaigns, application and infrastructure penetration tests.

2011/08 - 2014/09 Stockholm, SE

PWC SWEDEN | Manager

Heading Technical Security Assessments team; Forensic investigations; IT Governance & Security; Security and awareness trainings for PwC and clients; Compliance audits of Windows AD against industry standards.

EDUCATION

2005 – 2007 KTH ROYAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Stockholm, SE MSc. Information & Communication Systems Security

2001 – 2005 GALATASARAY UNIVERSITY

Istanbul, TR BSc. Computer Engineering

QUALIFICATIONS

Security CISSP Certified Information Systems Security Professional

OSCP Offensive Security Certified Professional

GPEN GIAC Penetration Tester *

GXPN GIAC Exploit Researcher and Advanced Penetration Tester *

GCFA GIAC Forensic Analyst *

G2700 GIAC ISO 27000 Specialist *

(*) certifications not renewed

Languages English Fluent

French Fluent
Swedish Fluent
Turkish Fluent

KEY SKILLS

Technical IT Security Red Team / Adversary Emulation / CBEST

Penetration Testing (Web / Infrastructure)

Application Security

Vulnerability Assessment

IT Forensics

Information Security Standards, Frameworks and Best Practices, including ISO

27001, NCSC Cyber Essentials, Common Criteria, MS Threat

Modelling, etc.

Security Training Offensive Security, Application Security, Security Awareness,

SANS Mentor (2012-2017)

Programming Ruby, Rails, Python, Java, C, C#, VB.NET, PHP, SQL, HTML,

Javascript, React, CSS, UI Frameworks (Bootstrap, Semantic

UI, Bulma)